Are you learning another language?
你正在学习另一门语言吗？
Maybe you’re trying to get to grips with it for work or study, or maybe you’re trying to master it just for the fun of it?
或许你是为了工作或学业而努力想要熟练掌握它，又或许你只是为了有趣而试图精通这门语言？
Language learning is nothing new, of course, but technology has made it easier than ever to grasp.
当然，语言学习并不是什么新鲜事，但科技的发展让它变得比以往任何时候都更容易上手。
The popularity of language-learning apps in particular has boomed around the world, especially as more people are working or studying at home.
尤其是语言学习类应用，其受欢迎程度在全球范围内迅速攀升，这一趋势在越来越多人居家办公或学习的背景下愈发明显。
They are usually easy and convenient to use because you can access them on your smartphone.
这类应用使用起来通常简便快捷，因为你可以在智能手机上随时使用。
And apps can offer languages not popular enough to be taught at evening classes or schools or universities.
此外，这些应用还能提供一些小众语言的学习资源，这类语言因受众不广，通常不会出现在夜校或各级院校的课程表中。
Many of us are aiming to be bilingual to enable us to communicate with people around the world.
我们很多人都立志成为双语使用者，这样就能与世界各地的人交流。
But, maybe surprisingly, it’s the British, who are not renowned for their enthusiasm for language learning, who are leading the way in the growth of these apps.
但或许会让人感到意外的是，在推动这类应用用户增长方面，领跑者竟然是英国人——这个群体素来不以语言学习的热情著称。
US firm Duolingo told the BBC that in 2020 new user numbers globally were up 67% compared with 2019, while in the UK they shot up by 132%, almost double the worldwide average.
美国公司多邻国向BBC透露，2020年其全球新增用户数量较2019年增长了67%，而英国地区的新增用户数量激增了132%，几乎是全球平均增幅的两倍。
And London-based Busuu, saw a similar trend for learners based in the UK.
总部位于伦敦的巴士英语学习平台，其英国用户数量也呈现出相似的增长趋势。
But for anyone trying their hand at a new language, what motivates them to carry on learning when there isn’t a teacher around to manage their progress?
但对于每一位尝试学习新语言的人来说，在没有老师监督学习进度的情况下，是什么激励着他们坚持下去呢？
Colin Watkins from Duolingo told the BBC that for UK learners at least, “people are learning because of culture, brain training, family, and relationships, along with school and travel.
多邻国的科林·沃特金斯在接受BBC采访时表示，至少对于英国的学习者而言，“人们学习语言的动因包括文化、训练大脑、家庭与人际关系，以及学业和旅行需求。
We want a positive use of our time, and to do something productive on our phones.”
我们都希望能高效利用时间，在手机上做一些有意义的事。”
The recent lockdowns have given us more time to do this.
近期的封锁措施让人们有了更多时间投入语言学习。
Certainly, becoming bilingual or a polyglot is a good thing, and it helps us to bring the world a little closer together.
毋庸置疑，掌握双语乃至多语是一件好事，它能帮助我们拉近世界的距离。